<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://blog.sbensu.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>sbensu</title><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/</link><description>On APIs, business, and random things I find interesting</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:32:36 -0300</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/friction-logs/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/friction-logs/</link><title>How to: friction logs</title><description>Most software is bad. I neither know why, nor how to solve the problem. Instead, the best I have to offer is a technique to keep the badness away for a while: friction logs.Friction logs are what they sound: a detailed log of everything that caused friction when using a product. This post teaches you how to make one. I recommend you to make one if:</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/lieutenants/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/lieutenants/</link><title>Lieutenants are the limiting reagent</title><description>The statement "this company lacks focus" confuses me. Don't companies hire more people in order to do more things? Shouldn’t the number of things the company can "focus" on expand as you hire?Clearly that is the case: Google has 100 products more than any new startup could have. But if anything, 100 products seems too few; after all, they have 200k employees! For reference, Instagram launched with less than 13 people. If Google were as efficient as Instagram was, they "should have" 150x more products.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/interfaces-for-logical-migrations/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/interfaces-for-logical-migrations/</link><title>Interfaces for logical migrations</title><description>This post explains how you can use interfaces to make data model and database migrations easier.Imagine you run a B2B company and Account represents how you want to bill each of your clients. Account is both a table in your database and an object in memory that has:</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/everybody-is-the-main-character/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/everybody-is-the-main-character/</link><title>Everybody is the main character</title><description>As a manager you are seen as the default main character of your team. In group meetings, you tell the collective story that guides everybody.But an important part of being a good manager1 is to have others be the main character as well. You should give each of your reports space to write their own individual story in one-on-ones. </description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/team-oriented-vs-outcome-oriented/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/team-oriented-vs-outcome-oriented/</link><title>Team-oriented, outcome-oriented</title><description> Maybe the real treasure was the friends we made along the way.  No, I want my fucking gold. In my career, I’ve found two different ways1 in which people are motivated:</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/api-breaking-changes/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/api-breaking-changes/</link><title>Breaking changes in JSON APIs</title><description>For an overall product development strategy, see How to avoid breaking APIs.When writing graphical user interfaces, the end user is a person. If the user interface changes overnight, the user might be surprised but they can adapt and react accordingly. Most software companies are used to changing their products often in various ways. API products don’t have this luxury.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/api-avoid-breaking-changes/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/api-avoid-breaking-changes/</link><title>How to avoid breaking APIs</title><description>When writing graphical user interfaces, the end user is a person. If the user interface changes overnight, the user might be surprised but they can adapt and react accordingly. Most software companies are used to changing their products often in various ways. API products don’t have this luxury.APIs are used by programs which can’t adapt to change. So, whenever you change an API, the change should be backwards compatible so that the new API version can be used by existing integrations.  For a list of breaking changes one can make to JSON APIs, see Breaking changes in JSON APIs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/payments-vs-transfers/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/payments-vs-transfers/</link><title>Payments vs Transfers</title><description>Every so often, somebody will tell me how crypto will render Visa and Mastercard obsolete. Crypto could do that one day but what we have today is not enough. Other people tell me that crypto is terrible, Visa is also terrible, and that payment fees should be absolutely zero. In both cases, when they run me through the logic, I often realize that they don't understand the difference between payments and transfers:</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/high-variance-management-math/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/high-variance-management-math/</link><title>Math intuitions on variance</title><description>This is a supplement to High Variance Management, where I build some intuition on the different probability distributions involved. Please read that post before reading this one.The normal and Gumbel probability distributions</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/high-variance-management/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/high-variance-management/</link><title>High Variance Management</title><description>There is a math supplement to this post where I build some intuition on the different probability distributions involved. If you are interested, read that later.Why variance matters</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/apis-as-ladders/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/apis-as-ladders/</link><title>APIs as ladders</title><description>Developers have opinions on what a good API1 is, but rarely have a shared vocabulary to describe what makes them good. This essay puts forward one set of considerations (out of many) that we started using at Stripe in 2019 to discuss API design2. You can find some of these concepts interspersed in this excellent blogpost by Michelle Bu.The hard part of an API is not to use it, but to learn it. After learning how the API works, typing out the commands is not hard. But when you first time you encounter an API, a million questions pop into your mind: What is this object for? Is there a parameter for that? Can the API do X? Learning requires effort, but the more the developer learns, the more problems they can solve. We can imagine the developers climbing a ladder where, for every step they take up the “learning ladder”3, the more problems they can solve.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/gift-card-marketplaces/</guid><link>https://blog.sbensu.com/posts/gift-card-marketplaces/</link><title>The secondary market in gift cards</title><description>This post by patio11 covers a few things that I learned working with gift cards over the years.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item></channel></rss>